http://www.air.org/page/privacy-policy

Skip to main content
You are hereHome
Privacy Policy
Thank you for visiting the American Institutes for Research (AIR) website and reviewing our Privacy Policy. We have updated our terms and internal processes to take into account new standards per the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), which went into effect on May 25, 2018.
You may visit our site without revealing any information about yourself.  However, if you are requesting information from AIR, we may have to collect personal information from you. AIR values its visitors' private information and understands the need for security and trust surrounding such information. Any personal information AIR collects is strictly for internal purposes only; we will never sell, trade, rent, share, or disclose any of your personal information to a third party without your consent, except in instances outlined in the “Legal Disclaimer” section.
This policy describes the types of information we may collect from you or that you may provide when you visit the website www.air.org and our practices for collecting, using, maintaining, protecting, and disclosing that information. This policy and statement generally applies to this website domain—www.air.org—and not to sites hosted outside of the www.air.org domain.
Information Collection and Use
Personal Information
AIR does not collect personal information about visitors to our website unless you explicitly choose to provide that information to us. We will use such information only for the purpose(s) stated at the time it is collected, and never for secondary or unrelated purposes unless otherwise requested or explicitly agreed to by the website user. In cases when such information is requested to provide a service or respond to an inquiry, visitors need to provide only the minimal information necessary. Typically, AIR will collect personal information for the following reasons:
To allow us to respond to inquiries and requests;
To allow us to process an event registration form;
To allow access to an informational electronic mailing list, newsletter, or database;
To contact you about the services on our site about which you have expressed interest; and/or
To send out newsletters, marketing emails, and other communications to which you have subscribed.
Applying to Work at AIR
When you apply online to work for AIR, we collect personal information from a variety of sources, including directly from you (e.g., when you contact us or complete an employment application) and from information we generate concerning you in the course of the application process. We also collect information from sources outside of AIR, for example, during the course of a background check. If an application for employment with AIR does not result in an offer of employment or you voluntarily withdraw from the application process, your application and personal information associated with the application is deleted from AIR’s database. If you have questions, you can contact AIR’s HR Service Center at 202.403.5500.
Surveys
Occasionally, AIR may provide the opportunity to participate in surveys on our site.  Participation in these surveys is completely voluntary. We use survey results to continue to improve this site and its content. If we use a third-party service to conduct the surveys, the service will be prohibited from using respondents’ personally identifiable information for any other purpose. AIR will never share personally identifiable information you provide through a survey with third parties unless there is some legal obligation to do so.
Website Traffic Information/Browser Cookies
When you visit our website on any device, we gather and temporarily store technical information about your visit. Our website servers log the standard information about website users including the device identifier, or IP address, of the user; domain of the user; URLs visited; the date/time you accessed our site; and other general demographic information. We use this information, which in itself is anonymous and does not identify individual users, solely to better understand visitor preferences and administer our site. We collect and use this information in aggregate form so that it cannot be manipulated to identify any particular individual user. AIR uses persistent cookies for one purpose only: to enable our analytics program to differentiate between new and returning visitors to our site. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser’s directions.
Opting Out
Visitors who would like to correct, update, or delete any personally identifiable information may do so using the Contact Us form on our website. Similarly, if you no longer wish to receive electronic newsletters or other communications, you may unsubscribe by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication. We will make every effort to promptly process all opt-out requests.
Third Party Links
This website contains third party links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by AIR. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the contents of any other websites. We encourage you to review the privacy policy and any other online policies of other websites that you link to, visit, or use.
Social Media
AIR uses third party social media sites to provide AIR content in formats that may be useful or interesting; however, www.air.org is the official source of information for the American Institutes for Research. AIR cannot attest to the accuracy of other information on social media or any other linked sites. Linking to these third party sites does not constitute an endorsement of the sponsors of these sites or the information presented on these sites by AIR or its employees.
Please be aware that the privacy protection provided at www.air.org may not be available on social media or other third party sites. You should review the privacy policies of all websites and social media outlets before using them and ensure that you understand how your information may be used. You should also adjust your account’s privacy settings on any third party website to match your preferences. Please note that when AIR uses social media sites, we do not collect or in any way use personally identifiable information.
Children’s Policy
Our website is not intended for children. AIR does not knowingly collect or solicit any information from anyone under the age of 13. No one under the age of 13 years may provide any information to this website. If we learn that we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact AIR using the Contact Us form on our website.
Security
Keeping Your Information Safe
The security of your personal information is important to us, and AIR is committed to ensuring that its Information Technology (IT) systems, applications, and IT infrastructure are secure. Unfortunately, despite our best efforts, the transmission of information via the internet is never completely secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee the security of your general or personal information transmitted to our website. Any transmission of personal information via our website is at your own risk. AIR does not assume any liability for third party use of your general or personal information, whether obtained legally or illegally from or through this website.
Compromise of Information
In the event that any personal information under AIR’s control is compromised as a result of a breach of security, we will take reasonable steps to investigate the situation, and, when appropriate, notify those individuals whose information may have been compromised and take other steps in accordance with applicable laws.
Legal Disclaimer
We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, property, or the safety of AIR employees, our clients or others, or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on the American Institutes for Research.
International Users
This website is hosted from the United States (U.S.). Users located outside of the U.S. consent to the transfer of their data to the U.S. for processing and use in accordance with this privacy policy.
Consent
By using our site, you consent to this website privacy policy.
Changes in this Privacy Statement
We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time. It is AIR’s policy to post any changes we make to our privacy policy on this page. The date the privacy policy was last revised is identified at the bottom of the page. You are responsible for periodically visiting our website and this privacy policy to check for any changes. Your continued use of this website after we make changes is deemed to be acceptance of those changes, so please check the policy periodically for updates.
Contact Us
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, our administrative practices, or other issues with our website, please contact us via email or at:
American Institutes for Research
1000 Thomas Jefferson St., N.W.
Washington, D.C. 20007
Phone: (202) 403-5000
This privacy policy was last updated July 16, 2018.
Share
